<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ASAP | Application Scalability And Performance</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/</link><description>Recent content on ASAP | Application Scalability And Performance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 09:13:34 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asap.ucar.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ASAP members awarded the Walter O. Roberts Scientific and Technical Advancement Award</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/walterrobertsaward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 09:13:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/walterrobertsaward/</guid><description>NSF NCAR&amp;rsquo;s High Altititue Obsersatory Laboratory (HAO) celebrated the collaborative MURaM project by awarding the team with the 2023 Walter O. Roberts Scientific and Technical Advancement Award for the Implementation of MURaM on Graphical Processing Units.</description></item><item><title>ASAP Member Featured in PBS Interview</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/pbs_interview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 15:10:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/pbs_interview/</guid><description>In late November Thomas Hauser (CISL), Daniel Swain (MMM), Summer Wasson (CISL), and Sheri Voelz (CISL) participated in interviews at NWSC with a film crew from the PBS series &amp;ldquo;Weathered&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title> Workshop on Correctness and Reproducibility for Climate and Weather Software</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/correctws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 11:24:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/correctws/</guid><description>November 9-10, 2023 at NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Mesa Laboratory
For more information, visit the workshop webpage!
Topics of interest include (but not limited to):
Tools and approaches for software testing, debugging, quality assurance, and continuous integration.</description></item><item><title>ASAP Member Featured Within the 'SuperComputing 2023 Celebrates Thirty-One Women in HPC' Series</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/womens-history-month-sc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 11:22:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/womens-history-month-sc/</guid><description>One member of the ASAP team was featured in the “SuperComputing 2023 Celebrates Thirty-One Women in HPC” series. Sheri was recognized for her contributions towards high-performance computing (HPC) in the field of Research Software Engineering (RSE).</description></item><item><title>EarthWorks</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/earthworks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 10:42:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/earthworks/</guid><description>EarthWorks’ goal is to develop a version of an Earth System Model (ESM) model that can run with a grid spacing of just a few kilometers.</description></item><item><title>SPERR Hackathon</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/sperr_hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 13:42:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/sperr_hackathon/</guid><description>On Feb 21, 2023, members from ASAP group and VAST group will attend OpenACC GPU Hackathons to optimize VAST&amp;rsquo;s SPERR data compressor with GPUs. OpenACC GPU Hackathons are 5-day events designed to help teams of three to six developers accelerate their own codes on GPUs with OpenACC or other tools.</description></item><item><title>Just-in-time(JIT) compilation on GPU for atmospheric chemistry</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/just-in-time_gpu_chemistry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 10:45:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/news/just-in-time_gpu_chemistry/</guid><description>Atmospheric chemistry solvers require efficient calculations of chemical forcing. To avoid using indirect addressing in these calculations, code-generating tools are often used to embed hard-coded indices into mechanism-specific functions.</description></item><item><title>Correctness and Verification</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/projects/verify/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 17:00:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/projects/verify/</guid><description>Summary
Model simulations are essential tools for understanding weather and climate. Many of these models are the result of multiple years or even decades of development, which has resulted in large and complex code bases that are still continually evolving.</description></item><item><title>Data Compression</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/projects/compression/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 09:19:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/projects/compression/</guid><description>Summary
Climate models such as the Community Earth System Model (CESM) typically produce enormous amounts of output data, and storage capacities have not increased as rapidly as processor speeds over the years.</description></item><item><title>MURaM</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 09:17:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram/</guid><description>MURaM is a numerical model that can be used to make detailed predictions about the Sun’s activity, and to understand the processes that drive solar variability.</description></item><item><title>MURaM IO</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram-io/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 10:32:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram-io/</guid><description>MURaM from NCAR HAO group is a numerical model to simulate star&amp;rsquo;s magnetic fields and their violent eruptions.
The MURaM IO is a project to improve scientific data Input/Output (IO) flexibility and performance of MURaM.</description></item><item><title>PUMAS</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/pumas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 15:23:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/pumas/</guid><description>Parameterization of Unified Microphysics Across Scales, short as PUMAS, is the cloud microphysics parameterization used in the Community Atmosphere Model (CAM). It is typically a computationally expensive component in an atmospheric model and thus improving its performance could save non-negligible computational resources.</description></item><item><title>CM1</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/cm1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/cm1/</guid><description>The Cloud Model version 1 is a mesoscale atmospheric model that allows for idealized studies of atmospheric phenomena. A new Lagrangian microphysics capability has been added which enables a significantly more accurate representation than the traditional bulk or multi-moment approaches frequently found in mesoscale atmospheric models.</description></item><item><title>ASAP</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/education/geocat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/education/geocat/</guid><description>Geoscience Community Analysis Toolkit (GeoCAT), established in 2019, is the project with several software tools developed in Python in order to lead the software engineering efforts of the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) Computational and Information Systems Lab (CISL)’s “Pivot to Python” initiative.</description></item><item><title>CLUBB</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/clubb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/clubb/</guid><description>CLUBB (Cloud Layers Unified By Binormals) is a parameterization of subgrid-scale (i.e. unresolved) variability in atmospheric models (Golaz et al. 2002a; Larson and Golaz 2005; Bogenschutz et al.</description></item><item><title>MPAS OpenACC</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/mpas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/mpas/</guid><description>Model for Prediction Across Scale (MPAS) Model for Prediction Across Scale is global meteorology and climate simulation model which consists of various components like atmosphere, ocean, sea-ice, land model along with appropriate physics packages to model various quantities of earth system.</description></item></channel></rss>