<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ASAP Software Projects on ASAP | Application Scalability And Performance</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/</link><description>Recent content in ASAP Software Projects on ASAP | Application Scalability And Performance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 16:48:28 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asap.ucar.edu/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EarthWorks</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/earthworks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 10:42:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/earthworks/</guid><description>EarthWorks’ goal is to develop a version of an Earth System Model (ESM) model that can run with a grid spacing of just a few kilometers.</description></item><item><title>MURaM</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 09:17:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram/</guid><description>MURaM is a numerical model that can be used to make detailed predictions about the Sun’s activity, and to understand the processes that drive solar variability.</description></item><item><title>MURaM IO</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram-io/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 10:32:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/muram-io/</guid><description>MURaM from NCAR HAO group is a numerical model to simulate star&amp;rsquo;s magnetic fields and their violent eruptions.
The MURaM IO is a project to improve scientific data Input/Output (IO) flexibility and performance of MURaM.</description></item><item><title>PUMAS</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/pumas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 15:23:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/pumas/</guid><description>Parameterization of Unified Microphysics Across Scales, short as PUMAS, is the cloud microphysics parameterization used in the Community Atmosphere Model (CAM). It is typically a computationally expensive component in an atmospheric model and thus improving its performance could save non-negligible computational resources.</description></item><item><title>CM1</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/cm1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/cm1/</guid><description>The Cloud Model version 1 is a mesoscale atmospheric model that allows for idealized studies of atmospheric phenomena. A new Lagrangian microphysics capability has been added which enables a significantly more accurate representation than the traditional bulk or multi-moment approaches frequently found in mesoscale atmospheric models.</description></item><item><title>CLUBB</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/clubb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/clubb/</guid><description>CLUBB (Cloud Layers Unified By Binormals) is a parameterization of subgrid-scale (i.e. unresolved) variability in atmospheric models (Golaz et al. 2002a; Larson and Golaz 2005; Bogenschutz et al.</description></item><item><title>MPAS OpenACC</title><link>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/mpas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://asap.ucar.edu/software/mpas/</guid><description>Model for Prediction Across Scale (MPAS) Model for Prediction Across Scale is global meteorology and climate simulation model which consists of various components like atmosphere, ocean, sea-ice, land model along with appropriate physics packages to model various quantities of earth system.</description></item></channel></rss>